Guide to the Leonid Hurwicz papers, 1911-2008 and undated RL.00599
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Leonid Hurwicz papers
1911-2008 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Hurwicz, Leonid
RL.00599
150 Linear Feet
Leonid Hurwicz (1917-2008) was Regents' Professor Emeritus of Economics at the University of Minnesota and recipient of the 2007 Nobel Memorial Prize in Economic Science for his work on mechanism design. The bulk of the Leonid Hurwicz papers span the years 1930-2008, covering his entire career as an economist, from his early work in the 1940s and 1950s at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT), the University of Chicago, and the Cowles Commission, until his death in 2008. The collection is arranged in the following series: Correspondence, Personal Files, Printed Materials, Professional Service, Research and Writings (about 70% of the collection), and Teaching Materials. Though there are correspondence, legal, financial, and other papers relating to Hurwicz's forced migration to the United States, there have been no items discovered documenting his training as an economist at the University of Warsaw or at the London School of Economics in the 1930s. The majority of the collection focuses on Hurwicz's work after 1970, most notably his collaborations with Stanley Reiter, Kenneth Arrow, Don Saari, Thomas Marschak and Marcel Richter.
Approx. 200,000 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Electronic files have been transferred to the electronic records server. Use copies of original electronic files must be made before contents can be accessed. Correspondence files must be screened before access can be granted.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Leonid Hurwicz Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008 and 2009. Accession 2017-0054 was a gift of Shomu Banarjee in 2017.
Biographical Note
Chronology
1917 Aug. 21 Leonid Hurwicz born in Moscow to Polish Jewish parents
1919 Family flees to Warsaw
1938 After studying the piano, economics, and physics, graduated with a law degree from the University of Warsaw
1938 Began studying at London School of Economics
1939 Took refuge in Geneva and emigrated to the United States a year later
1944-1946 Appointed as Research Associate at the Cowles Commission in Chicago, working chiefly on econometrics, a new field of study
1945 Published The Theory of Economic Behavior, American Economic Review, Vol. 35, No. 5, reprinted many times, most recently in 2004
1946-1949 Professor of Economics at Iowa State
1949-1951 Professor of Economics, Maths and Statistics, University of Illinois
1951-1999 Served as Professor of Economics and Mathematics in the School of Business Administration at the University of Minnesota
1958 Publication of Studies in Linear and Non-Linear Programming, edited by Kenneth J. Arrow, Leonid Hurwicz, and Hirofumi Uzawa, Stanford University Press
1961 Became chair of the University's Statistics Department
1971 Publication of Preferences, Utility,and Demand, edited by John S. Chipman, Leonid Hurwicz, Marcel K. Richter, and H. Sonnenschein, Harcourt Brace Jovanovic
1977 Published Studies in Resource allocation Processes, edited by Kenneth J. Arrow and Leonid Hurwicz, Cambridge University Press
1990 Awarded the National Medal of Science by President Bush
2006 Published Designing Economic Mechanisms, with Stanley Reiter, Cambridge University Press
2007 Oldest individual to be awarded the Nobel Prize in Economic Sciences, shared with Eric S. Maskin of Princeton University and Roger B. Myerson of the University of Chicago for mechanism-design theory
2008 June 26 Died at the age of 90 in Minneapolis
Collection Overview
The bulk of the Leonid Hurwicz Papers span the years 1930-2008, covering his entire career as an economist in the United States, from his early work at MIT, the University of Chicago and the Cowles Commission until his death while Emeritus Professor at the University of Minnesota. The collection is arranged in the following series: Correspondence, Personal Files, Printed Materials, Professional Service Series, Research and Writings, and Teaching Materials. Though there are correspondence, legal, financial, and other papers documenting his migration to the United States, there have been no items discovered that document his training as an economist at the University of Warsaw or at the London School of Economics. The majority of the collection focuses on Hurwicz's work after 1970, most notably his collaborations with Stanley Reiter, Kenneth Arrow, Don Saari, Thomas Marschak and Marcel Richter.
Though there is a significant amount of personal and professional correspondence, the majority of the papers reside in the 142 boxes of the Research and Writings Series, which contains extensive files of Hurwicz's research notes, reprints, and revisions of working papers by Hurwicz and others with added annotations. The research files document important developments in postwar mathematical economics and Hurwicz's seminal contributions to this field of study.
Recurring subjects in Research and Writings include Cowles-style econometrics; the stability of general equilibrium; the integrability of demand functions; the study of monopolies and oligopolies, as well as socialized systems; decision-making under ambiguity; the second welfare theorem; the applications of game theory to economic, social and political issues; and the development of mechanism design, for which Hurwicz was awarded the Nobel Prize in Economics in 2007. With his theories on mechanism design (including the notion of incentive-compatibility), Hurwicz analyzed the functioning of institutions and communication systems such as banking, auctions, and privatized markets, and compared political systems such as socialism and capitalism.
In addition to documenting Hurwicz's work in theoretical economics, the collection also follows his professional activities at the University of Minnesota, both as a teacher and as an active member of the Economics Department, his participation on various committees, and his work with institutions such as the Cowles Commission, RAND corporation, the National Science Foundation, and the American Academy of Arts and Sciences. Also in evidence is Hurwicz's interest in the development of foreign economies, with an emphasis on East Asia, Russia, and Eastern Europe. His numerous travels and presentations during his career as well as his continuous relations with European and Asian economists are documented chiefly in the Professional Service Series. Finally, the Printed Materials Series as well as the Research and Writings Series offer a significant amount of works by others documenting the development of recent economics. Many are heavily annotated by Hurwicz.
Electronic files which were readable have been transferred to the electronic records server. They consist chiefly of word processing documents containing drafts of Informational Efficiency, which Hurwicz co-authored with Reiter in the late 1990s. A use copy of original electronic files must be made before contents can be accessed; please contact Research Services before coming to use this material.
Detailed descriptions on the arrangement and content of each series can be found in the respective sections in this collection guide.
Related Material
Kenneth J. Arrow Papers, 1939-2007, bulk 1980s-2002 [many items of correspondence with Hurwicz and other related papers]
Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections, Duke University
Paul Samuelson Papers, 1939-2007, bulk 1980s-2002 [correspondence with Hurwicz]
Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections, Duke University
Econometrics; Economics, Mathematical; Economics -- Mathematical models; Economists -- Correspondence; Equilibrium (Economics); Game theory -- Research; Machine-readable records; Mathematical optimization; Monopolies -- Economic aspects; DVDs; World War, 1939-1945 -- Refugees -- Poland; CD-ROMs; Russia -- Economic conditions; Welfare economics -- Research; Demand functions (Economic theory) -- Mathematical models; Oligopolies -- Economic aspects; Europe, Eastern -- Economics; East Asia -- Economic conditions; Marschak, Thomas A. (Thomas Andrew); Massachusetts Institute of Technology. Dept. of Economics -- Faculty; Reiter, Stanley; Richter, Marcel K.; Saari, D. (Donald); University of Chicago. Dept. of Economics -- Faculty; University of Minnesota. Dept. of Economics -- Faculty; Uzawa, Hirofumi, 1928-; Arrow, Kenneth J. (Kenneth Joseph), 1921-2017; Cowles Commission for Research in Economics; Hurwicz, Leonid
- Correspondence Series, 1970-1980s, 22 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  Consists of two groupings of professional correspondence maintained by Hurwicz, chiefly from the 1970s and 1980s; there is electronic email as well dating from approximately 1998-2008. There is no significant difference between the two subseries of papers, except that the first is more focused on the 1980s and the second chiefly on the period from 1977-1979. The two collections overlap occasionally. There are a few attached reprints or notes. The files are arranged alphabetically by senders or recipients, or by subject.
  Though the files contain extensive correspondence between Hurwicz and his colleagues, these exchanges are for the most part routine and contain few extended conversations on economics. Original folder titles are retained. Additional and perhaps more significant correspondence may be found in the Research Files (particularly in the Arrow, Marschak, Reiter and Uzawa files), as well as in the Professional Service Series. A small but significant amount of correspondence regarding Hurwicz's immigration and earliest years in the United States is located in the Personal Files Series - much of this in Polish.
  - First Alphabetical Subseries
    - Academy of Independent Scholars (Box 1)
    - Aivazian (Box 1)
    - All-University Council (Box 1)
    - Allen, Beth (Box 1)
    - Altug, Summuru (Box 1)
    - American Academy of Arts and Science (Box 1)
    - American Economic Association (Box 1)
    - Agricultural Economics (Box 1)
    - Ai, Chunrong (Box 1)
    - Allen-Schutt, Edith (Box 1)
    - Amherst (Box 1)
    - American Express (Box 1)
    - Amit, Eilon (Box 1)
    - Ancient Law Study Group (Box 1)
    - Anderson, T.W. (Box 1)
    - Appleby, Joyce (Box 1)
    - Arrow, Kenneth (Box 1)
    - Arvan, Lanny (Box 1)
    - Assa, Isak (Box 1)
    - Baumol review (Box 1)
    - Beato, Pauline (Box 1)
    - Benjamin, Roger (Box 1)
    - Biomedical ethics (Box 1)
    - Biomedical Ethics (Box 2)
    - Blau, Julian (Box 2)
    - Bochniarz, Zbigniew (Box 2)
    - Bognano, M. (Box 2)
    - Bohr, P. Richard (Box 2)
    - Books return (Box 2)
    - Boughzala, Mondi (Box 2)
    - Braslau, David (Box 2)
    - Brodbeck, May (Box 2)
    - Brownlee (Box 2)
    - Bryant, John (Box 2)
    - Bryant, W.D.A. (Box 2)
    - Caldwell, J.L. (Box 2)
    - Calling Card (AT & T) (Box 2)
    - Carlson Chair Search committee (Box 2)
    - Campbell, Donald (Box 2)
    - Campus Club (Box 2)
    - Casio (Box 2)
    - Cass, David (Box 2)
    - Center for Advanced Studies in the Behavioral Sciences (Box 2)
    - Ancient Studies Center (Box 2)
    - Center for Austrian Studies (Box 2)
    - Center for Humanistic Studies (Box 2)
    - Center for Math Studies (Box 2)
    - Chakravotti (Box 2)
    - Champaign (Box 2)
    - Chander, Parkash (Box 2)
    - Chapra, Umer (Box 2)
    - Chernoff, Herman (Box 2)
    - China, 7 folders (Box 2)
    - Chipman, John (Box 2)
    - Chun, Youngsub (Box 2)
    - Civil Service, Sexual Harassment (Box 2)
    - Clayton, Thomas (Box 2)
    - Clarke, Simon (Box 2)
    - Cleveland, Harlan (Box 2)
    - Cliometrics (Box 2)
    - College of Liberal Arts, 12 folders (Box 3)
    - CBASSE, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - CBASSE - Food stamp program (Box 3)
    - CBASSE - Report on Women's employment and related social issues (Box 3)
    - Commitment to focus (Box 3)
    - Committee for Constitutional Integrity (Box 3)
    - Committee on Scholarly Communication with The People's Republic of China (Box 3)
    - Comstock, Ralph (Box 3)
    - Copies on Campus (Box 3)
    - Copyright Laws, 1977 (Box 3)
    - Cosgrove, John (Box 3)
    - Cornell University (Box 3)
    - Cossa (Box 3)
    - Cowles Commission (Box 3)
    - Cramton, Peter C. (Box 3)
    - Cura (Box 4)
    - Dahiya, S. Bhagwan (Box 4)
    - Dahms, L. (Box 4)
    - Dansby, Rbt (Box 4)
    - Davis, Lance (Box 4)
    - Debreu, Gerard (Box 4)
    - Decentralization conference (Box 4)
    - Diaz-Alejandro, C. (Box 4)
    - Distinguished teacher nominations (Box 4)
    - Dolan conference (Box 4)
    - Douglas, Edna (Box 4)
    - Easley, D. (Box 4)
    - Economics Dept., Folders 1-21 of 44
      - Constitution (Box 4)
      - Job Market (Box 4)
      - Faculty meetings (Box 4)
      - Executive committee (Box 4)
    - Economics Dept., Folders 22-44 of 44 (Box 5)
      - Visitors (Box 5)
      - Recruiting (Box 5)
      - Refunds (Box 5)
      - Meetings (Box 5)
    - Economic Indicators (Box 5)
    - Economic Report of the President (Box 5)
    - Economics Research Library Acquisitions (Box 5)
    - Econometric Society, 3 folders (Box 5)
    - El Salvador (Box 5)
    - Electronic Mails (Box 5)
    - Employee Benefits (Box 5)
    - Epstein, Roy (Box 5)
    - Escribano, Carlos (Box 5)
    - Evan Philadelphia Conference (Box 5)
    - Expenses, Washington D.C., 1982 (Box 5)
    - Faber, Malte (Box 5)
    - Faculty Mortgage Program (Box 5)
    - Faculty Tenures (Box 6)
    - Faculty retirement plan (Box 6)
    - Faculty travel funds (Box 6)
    - Fan, L.S. (Box 6)
    - Federal Reserve (Box 6)
    - Feiwel, George (Box 6)
    - Feng, Shan (Box 6)
    - Feng, Yu Zhong (Box 6)
    - Foreign Report, 1985 (Box 6)
    - Foreign Report, 1986 (Box 6)
    - Film Rentals (Box 6)
    - Finkler, Merton (Box 6)
    - Fisher and Taussig Awards (Box 6)
    - Foreman Committee (Box 6)
    - Fraser for Mayor (Box 6)
    - Freixas, X. (Box 6)
    - Friedman, Harvey (Box 6)
    - Frucht, Padraic (Box 6)
    - Fulbright (Box 6)
    - Future of Public Education in Minnesota (Box 6)
    - Gadsby, Dwight M. (Box 6)
    - Gao Shangquan (Box 6)
    - Geanakoplos, John (Box 6)
    - Gerrard, Christopher D. (Box 6)
    - Gerstein Committee, 5 folders (Box 6)
    - Gidwan, Sushila (Box 6)
    - Gilboa, Ithzak (Box 6)
    - Goldman, Jay (Box 6)
    - Goodrich, Charles (Box 6)
    - Goslin, David (Box 6)
    - Gottinger, Hans, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Graduate School, 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Graduate School - GRAC (Box 7)
    - Graduate School - Sexual Harassment (Box 7)
    - Green, Jerry (Box 7)
    - Greensberg, Joseph (Box 7)
    - Groves, Ted (Box 7)
    - Guggenheim Foundation, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Hahn, Frank (Box 7)
    - Hammond, Peter (Box 7)
    - Harman lunch (Box 7)
    - Harris, Milton (Box 7)
    - Hart, Sergiu (Box 7)
    - Hartley, Michael (Box 7)
    - Harvard University - Society of Fellows (Box 7)
    - Haskell and Stern Associates (Box 7)
    - Hay, Philip (Box 7)
    - Health Issues (Box 7)
    - Heller, Walter P. (Box 7)
    - Heller, Walter W. (Box 7)
    - Heller, Walter P./Starr NSF Proposal (Box 7)
    - Hewlett-Packard (Box 7)
    - Hildreth, C. (Box 7)
    - Hitch, Charles (Box 7)
    - Ho, Manuscript Printing (Box 7)
    - Holt, Charles (Box 7)
    - Holmstrom, Bengt (Box 7)
    - Holt, Robert (Box 7)
    - Holt Seminar, 1979 (Box 7)
    - Hong Kong Branch, Holt Publishing Company (Box 7)
    - Hori, Hajime (Box 7)
    - Horwitz, Frances (Box 7)
    - Horsley, A (Box 7)
    - Howe, Charles (Box 7)
    - Hurbermon - Paper Review for Proceeding (Box 7)
    - Human Rights Center (Box 7)
    - Hurwicz, Abraham (Box 7)
    - Hurwicz's commitments
      - Concordia University, 1989 (Box 7)
      - Woody Thompson Lectures (Box 7)
      - Conference in honor of L. McKenzie (Box 7)
      - Coordination Theory Workshop, 1988 (Box 7)
      - Workshop on Effective Content of Mathematical Models in the Behavorial Sciences, UC Irvine, 1988 (Box 7)
      - Barcelona Honorary Degree, 1988 (Box 7)
      - New York University Oskar Morgenstern Visiting Fellow, 1990 (Box 7)
      - Indonesia Expenses (Box 7)
      - Indonesia (Box 8)
      - World Congress for Soviet and East European Studies, 1990 (Box 8)
      - Jacob Schodler Memories Lectures (Box 8)
      - SIAM, 1988 (Box 8)
      - Mechanical Engineering Seminar, 1988 (Box 8)
      - Tokyo roundtable, 1987 (Box 8)
      - Northwestern University visit, 1988-1989 (Box 8)
      - Decentralization Conference, New York, 1987 (Box 8)
      - Tokyo, 1986 August (Box 8)
      - Letters from Susan Walz (LH's secretary) in China (Box 8)
      - China Trip, 1986 (Box 8)
      - Cal Tech, 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Hurwicz's papers publication
      - Hart, Aumann "Handbook of Game Theory" chapter on implementation (Box 8)
      - Workshop on the effective content of mathematical models (Box 8)
      - Saarlandes "general discussion," 1989 (Box 8)
      - Hurwicz/Walker, Econometrica (Box 8)
      - Hurwicz/Thomson, Journal of Complexity (Box 8)
      - Hurwicz, Joan Robinson Project, ed. by Feiwel (Box 8)
      - Hurwicz/Weinberger, decentralization (Box 8)
      - Hurwicz, American Mathematical Monthly (Box 8)
      - Fox festschrift (Box 8)
      - Irrational Societies (Box 8)
      - Palgrave, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Journal of Complexity, Hurwicz/Marschak (Box 9)
      - Koopmans essay (Box 9)
      - International Journal of Development Planning Literature (Box 9)
      - Reprint Requests (Box 9)
      - CATO conference (Box 9)
      - Handbook: Intriligator (Box 9)
    - Hurwicz - Committees
      - CLA consultative committee, 1983 (Box 9)
      - Committee on Economic Theory, 1989 (Box 9)
      - Carlson Chair Committee (Box 9)
      - Executive Committee, 1986-7 (Box 9)
    - Hurwicz - Personal files and commitments
      - Curriculum vitae (Box 9)
      - Visa (Box 9)
      - Carlson Chair (Box 9)
      - Conference on the theory of incentives (Box 9)
      - Faculty activity reports, 1983-1985, 1991-1997, 6 folders (Box 9)
      - Elementary Chinese classes (Box 9)
      - Israel, 1978 (Box 9)
      - Salary/appointment (Box 9)
      - Boulder and Berkeley, 1982 (Box 9)
      - Family Tree (Box 9)
      - Honorary Degree - Northwestern University (Box 9)
      - Daily article, 1978 (Box 9)
      - Various personal files (Box 9)
      - University of California, Santa Cruz (Box 9)
      - State University of NY at Albany, 2 folders (Box 9)
      - Vanderbilt University (Box 9)
      - Southern Illinois University (Box 9)
      - MBA lectures (Box 9)
      - Center for Control Sciences (Box 10)
      - Professional activities, 1981-1982 (Box 10)
      - Daily article, senate meeting, 1978, 2 folders (Box 10)
      - Newspapers clippings (Box 10)
      - Distinguished fellow AEA (Box 10)
      - Personal Economics / Meteorology (Box 10)
      - Royalties (Box 10)
      - Solidarnosc (Box 10)
      - India, 1981 (Box 10)
      - References (Box 10)
    - Hurwicz - Unattended commitments
      - Search committee, dean of graduate school (Box 10)
      - Latin AEA, Morende Felipe, 1989 (Box 10)
      - Decentralization Conference, 1983 (Box 10)
      - University Senate - Nominating committee (Box 10)
      - Managing Change in East-Asia, 1987 (Box 10)
      - Vandereer Speaker at IL University (Box 10)
      - Commitments, unable to meet (Box 10)
      - Past Activities (Box 10)
    - Hurwicz, Maxim (Box 10)
    - Hurwicz, Margo (Box 10)
    - Ikeda, Takanobu (Box 10)
    - Inada, Ken-Ichi (Box 10)
    - Indian Dance (Box 10)
    - Indonesia, Second University, Development Projet, 1981 (Box 10)
    - Inloading, 1983 (Box 10)
    - Institute for Empirical Macroeconomics (Box 10)
    - Institute for Mathematics and Its Applications (Box 10)
    - Insurance: travel (Box 10)
    - International Research and Exchange Board (Box 10)
    - Intriligator (Box 10)
    - Ioannides, Yannis (Box 10)
    - ITO (letters) (Box 10)
    - Iwanska, Alicji (Box 10)
    - Iyengar, NS (Box 10)
    - Jacob Schmookler Memorial lectures, 1976 (Box 10)
    - Jaffé, Williamson (Box 10)
    - Jerison, Michael (Box 10)
    - Jerison - Fulbright (Box 11)
    - Jones, Will T. (Box 11)
    - Jordan, James (Box 11)
    - Journal of Complexity (Box 11)
    - Journal of Mathematical Economics (Box 11)
    - Journal of Political Economy (Box 11)
    - Judaic Studies (Box 11)
    - Kahn, Alfred (Box 11)
    - Kahn, Donald (Box 11)
    - Kahng, Sun, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Kalai, Ehud (Box 11)
    - Kannai, Y, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Kantorovitch, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Katzner, Donald (Box 11)
    - Keller - A commitment to focus (Box 11)
    - Kelly, Jerry (Box 11)
    - Kelton, Chris (Box 11)
    - Kermit (Box 11)
    - Kim, Chon Sak (Box 11)
    - Kingston conference (Box 11)
    - Kline, Jerry (Box 11)
    - Klein, L. (Box 11)
    - Koffler, H. (Box 11)
    - Koopmans, T. (Box 11)
    - Kluwer Publishing (Box 11)
    - Koyama, Koicki (Box 11)
    - Kurz Mordecai, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Laffont - St-Pierre Review (Box 11)
    - Lains, Sir Hector (Box 11)
    - Lakshman, T.K. (Box 11)
    - Lambert - Feder Chair of Public Choice Theory (Box 11)
    - Last Week in Brief (Box 11)
    - Leavitt, Michael (Box 11)
    - Ledyard, John (Box 11)
    - Lee, Man-Woo (Box 11)
    - Lee, Young-Whan (Box 11)
    - Leontief, Wassily (Box 11)
    - Lewis, Alain (Box 12)
    - Lewis, Harriet (Box 12)
    - Li, Shue (Box 12)
    - Library of Congress (Box 12)
    - Library Proxy Cards (Box 12)
    - Lin, S.K. (Box 12)
    - Library - Bibliography (Box 12)
    - Library Committee (Box 12)
    - Lilly MBA (Box 12)
    - Lindgren, Bernard (Box 12)
    - Listings (Box 12)
    - Los, Jerzy (Box 12)
    - Lukermann, Fred (Box 12)
    - Madrid, Arturo (Box 12)
    - Magrath, C. Peter, 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Mah, Yun-Zhong (Box 12)
    - Majundar, Mukul (Box 12)
    - Makowski, Louis (Box 12)
    - Malinvaud, Edmond (Box 12)
    - Malone, Thomas W. (Box 12)
    - Malueg, David A. (Box 12)
    - Mankin, Wyatt (Box 12)
    - Manuscript Service (Box 12)
    - Margolis, Julius (Box 12)
    - Marschak, Thomas (Box 12)
    - Marteus, J.F. (Box 12)
    - Mas-Colell, Andreu (Box 12)
    - Maskin, E. (Box 12)
    - Mathematics Dept. Colloquium (Box 12)
    - Mathematics Review (Box 12)
    - Mathematics, Statistics Books (Box 12)
    - Matsuo, Toshihide (Box 12)
    - MBA Presentations (Box 12)
    - McKelvey, Richard (Box 12)
    - McKelvey, Robert (Box 12)
    - Medal of Science (Box 12)
    - Mehta, G. (Box 12)
    - Merwin, Jack (Box 12)
    - Microcomputers (Box 12)
    - Midwest Math Economic Conference (Box 12)
    - Miller, Bill (Box 13)
    - Millward-Brown, Ian (Box 13)
    - Minnesota Economic Association (Box 13)
    - Minnesota Daily (Box 13)
    - Minnesota Forum (Box 13)
    - Minnesota, Univ. of (Box 13)
    - MMPI (Box 13)
    - Mitygain, Boris (Box 13)
    - Miura, Rei (Box 13)
    - Moe, Donald, State Senator (Box 13)
    - Mohan, Krishna (Box 13)
    - Mohring, H., 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Montias, John (Box 13)
    - Montreal (Box 13)
    - Morgan, James (Box 13)
    - Moscow (Box 13)
    - Moulin (Box 13)
    - Hervé (Box 13)
    - MST Review (Box 13)
    - Munth, Dr. Preben (Box 13)
    - Murphy, Paul (Box 13)
    - NAS (National Academy of Sciences), 3 folders (Box 13)
    - National Research Council, 3 folders (Box 13)